Guide to the George Kirksey Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Photographs, [1910-1971]
  - Harry Craft giving outfield candidates instructions in throwing (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Cot Deal going over pitching form with Darrell Brandon (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Paul Richards with Colt 45's player (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Eddie Robinson giving batting instructions to Jim Cope (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Paul Richards giving batting instructions to Joe Morgan and Sonny Jackson, while Lou Fitzgerald looks on (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Paul Richards with Colt 45's player (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Luman Harris instructing Jerry Ard and Steve Hertz, in foot position in taking a lead off third base (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Batting practice (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Grady Hatton giving Ivan Murrell batting instruction during school at Colt Stadium (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Paul Richards and Hal (Skinny) Brown giving personal instruction to Jay Dahl before his first major league start (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Four members of the Colt 45's staff giving instruction to Jay Dahl (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Billy Goodman giving Walter Williams tips on how to hold the bat and batting stance during September school (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Dave Philley giving bunting instruction to Joe Morgan, Brock Davis, and Sonny Jackson, during September school at Colt Stadium (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Aerial view of the maximum capacity crowd and parking at Colt Stadium (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Colt 45's players Ernie Fazio and Rusty Staub (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Luman Harris working with Chris Zachary on his curve ball (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Harry Craft giving pitching instructions to a group of rookie pitchers (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Paul Richards instructing infielders on how to touch second base on double play at spring training camp (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Jim Busby instructing Brock Davis in catching fly balls (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Paul Richards giving instructions to young catchers (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Billy Jurges working with Glenn Vaughn in tagging second on a double play (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Mike White receiving a flu shot by Jim Ewell (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Jim Busby discussing outfield play with Brock Davis (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Billy Jurges talking to Sonny Jackson during a break for lunch at Apache Junction, Arizona, training camp (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Travel, [1933] (Box 15, Folder 52-56)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 15, Folder 57-70)
  - George Kirksey, Roy Hofheinz, and Billy Graham (Box 15, Folder 58)
- Scrapbooks, 1920-1968
  There are nine scrapbooks in this series, dating from 1920 through 1968. Materials in the scrapbooks include newspaper clippings, tearsheets, invitations, identification cards, and photographs. Much of the material is neither dated nor identified. The first six scrapbooks cover Kirksey's life, primarily the 1920s through the 1960s. The remaining scrapbooks were compiled by Billie Joyce (Smith) Kirksey. The first scrapbook is in poor condition. Items include carbon copies of Kirksey's earliest sports articles, clippings of many of his articles from the 1920s and early 1930s, Christmas cards, tickets and badges from various sporting events, and photographs. Extreme caution must be used while working with this scrapbook. The second scrapbook includes clippings of stories written by Kirksey, photographs related to his travels in 1933 and his family, and letters received by Kirksey. There are also miscellaneous items. Items are dated 1931-1938. The third scrapbook covers Kirksey's military career during World War II and covers 1942 through 1945. Most of the items are newspaper clippings written by Kirksey or about Kirksey. Included are stories about his service and announcements of his awards. There are also numerous photographs taken during his time in service. Some of the photographs have captions included. The fourth scrapbook focuses on his work with the Houston Sports Association but includes materials on Kirksey's travels in Europe and on Kirksey's auto racing team which he started in 1966. The scrapbook includes clippings about the Colt .45s, articles written by Kirksey, photographs, press material, letters, and ephemeral items. Items are dated 1951-1968. The fifth scrapbook is titled, "Houston Professional Football, Inc." and includes clippings regarding Kirksey's work to bring professional football to Houston. All clippings are from 1959. Some items are loose. The sixth scrapbook is titled, "Anti-Baseball Book, 1965." In it are clippings detailing the perceived demise of baseball. There are also loose clippings that have been kept with the scrapbook. Clippings are dated 1964 through 1965. The three remaining scrapbooks were compiled by Kirksey's second wife, Billie Joyce (Smith) Kirksey. These include clippings related to Billie Joyce's activities at the University of Houston while she was a student. The first scrapbook includes the 1945-1946. The second scrapbook focuses on 1946-1947. The third focuses on 1947-1949. Items included are newspaper clippings, graduation announcements, wedding announcements, invitations, cards, and favors. These two scrapbooks are in poor condition.
  - Scrapbook, [1920-1930] (Item 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1938 (Item 2)
  - World War II Scrapbook, 1942-1945 (Item 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1951-1968 (Item 4)
  - Houston Professional Football Scrapbook, 1959 (Item 5)
  - Anti-Baseball Book, 1964-1965 (Item 6)
  - Billie Joyce (Smith) Kirksey Scrapbook, 1945-1946 (Item 7)
  - Billie Joyce (Smith) Kirksey Scrapbook, 1946-1947 (Item 8)
  - Billie Joyce (Smith) Kirksey Scrapbook, 1947-1949 (Item 9)
- Miscellaneous, [1940?-1971]
  This series includes items of an ephemeral nature, collected in one box for safekeeping. Items are not dated. There are 9 items in this series. Included are a handkerchief, a copper-colored piece of metal, two attaché cases, two wallet-sized photograph holders, and a binder. There is also a certificate that has been placed in the box because it is oversized, as well as an envelope containing coins from various European countries.
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 16)